A Guide to the Papers of the Low Moor Iron Company
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Records
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M-V", incl. Universal Film Exchange movies, orders, sales and complaints, 1914 Feb. -1925 Nov. (Box Box 105)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence intra-company, orders and weekly reports from Kay Moor Supt., 1916 April -1917 Sept. (Box Box 105)
  - Phillip Isham, 1918 Feb. -1923 Dec. (Box Box 105)
  - Ross Howell from Hibbart - shipping orders, 1923 Jan. -Dec. (Box Box 105)
  - Jones & Laughlin Steel - prices and orders for iron, steel beams and rails, 1909 May -1912 Sept. (Box Box 105)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-C", incl. sales of iron and limestone and purchases of track and trestles, 1910 May -1925 Feb. (Box Box 105)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D-L", incl. Eaton Rhodes, Hunter Frickshorn, coke sales and orders, 1910 March -1925 March (Box Box 105)
  - J. W. Montieth, manager of mines proposed land leasing, sales, production, timber survey, maintenance problems, 1916 Aug. -1920 Jan. (Box Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-W", incl. Jordan Washers, ore analysis, inventories, washer parts, pulleys at Jordan, washer inquiries, 1916 Oct. -1918 May (Box Box 106)
  - Dalton - Treasurer, incl. accounts receivable, payable, investors, raw materials, credit and debit statement for 1917, 1916 Oct. -1919 Dec. (Box Box 106)
  - Lake Superior Iron Ore Assoc., 1919 April -1920 Jan. (Box Box 106)
  - Walter Wallingford & Co. - orders, sales inquiries, weekly market reports, 1920 Jan. -Dec.; (2 folders) (Box Box 106)
  - J. A. Hibbart - Prod. Statistics, 1924 Dec. -1925 Dec. (Box Box 106)
  - Regional and U. S.; Production Figures, incl. information on coal production, 1925 Jan. -Dec. (Box Box 106)
  - National Coal Assoc. Newsletter, Virginia Mfg. Assoc., incl. production market information, speeches at conventions, information on coal production, etc., 1925 Jan. -June (Box Box 106)
  - New River Coal Operators Assoc. production, transport problems, labor problem, union injunction, petitions to ignore union representative (Oct. 31, 1921), Union Injunction by Borderland Coal, 1916 July -1922 Jan. (Box Box 106A)
  - E. H. Deacon, R. S. Lackey, G. W. Lipscomb - wages disbursed, charges against individuals, costs of some materials, 1916 Dec. -1919 Dec. (Box Box 106A)
  - Slag to buy and sell, 1916 Oct. -1919 May (Box Box 106A)
  - Oriskany Ore & Iron Corp., Lavino Furnace Co. - Contract - Sinter from Pyrite Residue, standard correspondence enquiries on price, availability, 1917 June -1919 Dec. (Box Box 106A)
  - Letterbook - correspondence to Charles Hubbard & Co. - orders, accounts, paid and payable, dates of arrival, problems with deliveries, 1887 April -1888 Nov. (Box Box 107)
  - Low Moor Letterbook - correspondence by Low and Means, 1873 Oct. -1880 Nov. (Box Box 107)
  - Letterbook - correspondence by G. T. Wickes - cost problems, furnace construction, operations - day by day in places, labor, shipping, etc., 1879 Jan. -1880 Jan. (Box Box 107)
  - Burnley Bros. - coal, wood, etc. - prices, orders, shipment schedule, 1915 Oct. -1917 April (Box Box 108)
  - Walter Wallingford - sales, orders, quality control problems, prices and competition, market conditions, 1906 Dec. -1907 Jan. (Box Box 108)
  - Nash, Isham & Co. - sales, orders, quality control, competition, market conditions, price negotiations, inventory problems, Southern competition, question of altering composition of metal, transportation problems, 1901 March -1909 March; (4 folders) (Box Box 108)
  - Adams Bros.-Paynes Co. - problems with quality control, 1915 Oct. -1916 Nov. (Box Box 108)
  - Guy DuVal - Treasurer's reports transfers of funds, stockholder's meeting, stock transfers, 1915 July -1916 June (Box Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-D", incl. corporate correspondence, sales purchases, information for Bradstreets, Virginia tax problem, 1913 May -1917 Dec. (Box Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-I" incl. Covington Machines, Hunter Frischkorn, Bloomsburg Locomotive Works, Ingersoll-Rand, Banks Supply Co., 1918 May -1924 June (Box Box 108)
  - Purchasing agent miscellaneous correspondence, 1902 Dec -1919 Aug (Box Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "I-W", incl. Post-Glover Electric Co., H. K. Porter Co., orders, deferrals of orders, 1918 Sept. -1924 April (Box Box 109)
  - Lipscomb, Jordan Mine activity, 1911 July -Sept. (Box Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-L", incl. purchasing agent - assistant treasurer mostly, Ingersoll-Rand, Covington Machinery, L. B. Foster, Charleston Electrical, 1916 Dec. -1923 April (Box Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H-Q", incl. purchasing agent, receipt of Jordan notices, Covington Machine, Queen City Supply Co., Ingersoll-Rand, 1916 Aug. -1917 Nov. (Box Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, incl. Industrial Commission of Virginia, purchasing agent or assistant treasurer, claim on injuries, Charleston Electrical, orders, sales, Banks Supply, Hunter Frischkorn, Aetna Explosives, Ingersoll-Rand, Jeffrey Mfg. Co., Nash, Isham & Co., W. E. Hall, 1911 Feb. -1927 Aug.; (3 folders) (Box Box 109)
  - Purchasing agent - Nash Isham, market analysis, Madison Machine, Foundry, Banks and Supply, 1911 June -1920 Feb (Box Box 110)
  - General correspondence, Walter Wallingford - inquiries and sales, traffic manager - information on shipments, 1917 March -1920 Dec. (Box Box 110)
  - Purchasing agents, General Manager correspondence - some assistant treasurer, Nash-Isham, Jeffrey Mfg. Co., 1910 April -1920 Nov. (Box Box 110)
  - Purchasing agents - Philip Isham and Walter Wallingford, traffic manager to Ross Howard and Walter Wallingford, shipment of orders, 1921 May -1923 Dec. (Box Box 110)
  - Orders and correspondence, Eaton Rhodes - orders, Ross Howard, traffic manager - manipulates shipping schedules, Allis-Chalmers, Westinghouse, Clifton Forge Lumber, 1920 Oct. -1923 Dec. (Box Box 110)
  - Orders and correspondence, Cargill, assistant treasurer and purchasing agent, E. L. Jones - eviction on renters company houses, Jones-Kessler-E. C. Means, Phillip Isham and Eaton-Rhodes, Ross Howells and Bateman, 1906 May -1923 April (Box Box 110)
  - Purchasing agents correspondence, incl. Walter Wallingford & Co., C. C. Means, Divguid Bros., Wholesale and Retail Dealers, Covington Machine Co., F. V. Hunbart, president and general manager Jeffrey Mfg. Co., South Side Foundry, Link-Bett, George Anderson of Longdale - traffic manager, 1902 Sept. -1924 Jan.; (4 folders) (Box Box 111)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E-F", incl. assistant treasurer and purchasing agent correspondence, Hugh Dalton treasurer, 1915 Dec. -1925 Dec. (Box Box 111)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D-F", incl. assistant treasurer correspondence, 1921 March -Dec. (Box Box 111)
  - Walter Wallingford - traffic manager, orders, specifications on quality, 1918 Feb -March (Box Box 111A)
  - Purchasing agent correspondence, Joseph Dixon Crucible, C. W. Dillon - Means Politics in Virginia - Republican, Dings Electro-Magnetic Separator Co. recover metal from ore, Eagle Smelting Dillon & Sons - Limestone, J. X. Dummik & Co. - Sales Representative - Philadelphia is home office, 1909 March -1914 March (Box Box 111A)
  - Nash, Isham - sales reports and requests difficulties in sales and collection during 1908 recession, 1908 Feb. -June, 1911 March -July, 1909 March; (2 folders) (Box Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-S", incl. correspondence of suppliers of Low Moor and Low Moor solicitation of bids on needed goods - steel, raw iron, machine parts, limestone, lumber, 1919 Sept. -Nov. (Box Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E", incl. Assistant Treasurer Cargill, Foster Motor Car Co., Electric Ore Separator Co., Stephen A. Ellison & Co. - coal, 1910 March -1914 May (Box Box 112)
  - Dolly Ann Mine Correspondence - job inquiries, petitions for damages, labor wages and problems, 1911 July -1915 Feb. (Box Box 112)
  - J. Eichleay, Jr. & Co. incl. steel castings - orders by Low Moor, requests on prices, problems in use and questions about fabrication of new castings, 1912 April -Oct. (Box Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B-W", incl. general managers correspondence, Eagle Rock Lime Co. - offers of supply of limestone, prices, etc., bills and solicitations of new business from Low Moor, 1907 March -1920 Oct. (Box Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-W", incl. purchasing agent correspondence, Ingersoll-Rand, Atlas Powder, Barker Jennings, Bell Locomotive, Hunter Frischkorn, 1916 Feb. -1925 June; (3 folders) (Box Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-M", incl. purchasing agent, Miller Supply Co., Queen City Supply, Powder Suppliers, 1917 Feb. -Dec. (Box Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P", incl. traffic manager correspondence, Assistant manager, Philip Isham - orders from sales agent, terms, shipping inquiries for Nash, Isham, Walter Wallingford, C. & O. Railroad, 1912 Sept. -1926 Feb. (Box Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-W", incl. traffic manager and president correspondence, Dalton Nash and Walter Wallingford, C. & O. Railroad, 1907 Jan. -1923 May (Box Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D-E", incl. assistant treasurer, Pickinson Fire Brick, Eimer & Amend, Edgar Zinc Co., 1910 Feb. -1914 July (Box Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D-P", incl. traffic manager and purchasing agent correspondence, Phillips Isham, Diamond Powder, Joseph Ryerson, 1911 July -1924 Nov. (Box Box 113)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. H. G. Merry - general managers correspondence, Fenwick Mine Production, Macon-Miller Levertacks, railway equipment, job enquiries, Mosley & Smith Wholesale Hardware, Simmons - $10,000 damages claimed, Low Moor supplier correspondence, Isaac Morris - trial on damages, testimony, Thornton N. Motley - Supplier, 1895 Aug. -1901 Feb.; (3 folders) (Box Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L-M", incl. H. G. Merry - general manager and assistant treasurer correspondence, Miners oil used at Low Moor, timber and steel rails suppliers, 1896 June -1906 April (Box Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. assistant treasurer and E. C. Means - President correspondence, Library Bureau - on cross-referencing files, Fenwick Mine shipments, 1904 April -1906 April (Box Box 114)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. H. G. Merry correspondence, Best-Fox Bronze Dealers, Bertha Mine Co. zinc - principle material folder, cost, lab analysis, shipments, W. Bingham - Wholesales Hardware & Metals - Cleveland, C. C. Blake - Wholesale Coal & Coke - Cincinnati, 1896 Feb. -1900 Feb.; (2 folders) (Box Box 114A)
  - Laidlow-Dunn-Gordon, Link-Belt Engineering, correspondence with H. G. Merry, compressor blueprints, 1904 March -1906 June (Box Box 114A)
  - A. Leschen & Sons, Lavell & Gaw, correspondence with H. G. Merry, extensive collection correspondence of orders and sales to and from Low Moor, 1903 Dec. -1906 June (Box Box 114A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "U", incl. Means & Cargill, president and assistant treasurer correspondence, U.S. Geological Survey, Appalachian region, Union Line, Union Petroleum Co. sales, etc., State Corp. Commission difficulties, failure to report on Low Moor Railroad operations, 1902 Nov. -1904 Nov. (Box Box 115)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "V", incl. Means & S. Cargill - president and assistant treasurer correspondence, Virginia Iron, Coal & Coke Co., Virginia Bridge & Iron, Virginia Machine Co., Vulcan Iron Works, Virginia Iron & Coal, Virginia-Carolina Chemical Co., 1902 Jan. -1904 Oct.; (3 folders) (Box Box 115)
  - C. & O. Coal & Coke Co., Means correspondence - president, problems of sales, orders, etc., 1902 June -1903 July (Box Box 116)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry and S. G. Cargill, Bodley Wagon Co., Broderick & Bascom Rope Co., production shipments, sales, prices, inventories in various months, 1899 Nov. -1925 Sept; (2 folders) (Box Box 116)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B-C", incl. Means and Cargill - President and Asst. Treasurer, F. K. Bowes, Iron, Steel, Nails, Broderick & Bascom special secret discount (10%) to Low Moor, 1900 Jan. -1906 Dec. (Box Box 116)
  - C. & O. Railway, incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry and S. Cargill, traffic tariff changes, shipment of coal, problems of availability of cars principle rate changes, disagreements, 1893 July -1895 Dec.; (4 folders) (Box Box 117)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. Merry and Cargill - correspondence, 11th Census - Mines and Mining, H. B. Clafton of New York City - 2 page diatribe against silver, 1890 Jan. -1895 Oct. (Box Box 117)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. correspondence with Cargill and Means, 1904 Dec. -1906 Dec. (Box Box 118)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. H. G. Merry correspondence with G. W. Schultz, Charles Scott Spring Co., Safety Fire Extinguisher Co., Schenectady Locomotive Works, 1893 Feb. -1906 Jan.; (2 folders) (Box Box 118)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry and S. G. Cargill, invoices, American Bridge & Iron, American Forcite Powder Mfg. Co., American Cotton Oil Co., American Roofing Co., Atlas Car & Manufacturing Co., Ashland Fire Brick, Allegheny Ore & Iron Co., American Car & Foundry Co., Allegheny Iron Co., Aetna Powder Co., Armory & Co., Argand Refining Co. Petroleum, 1887 Feb. -1906 Dec.; (5 folders) (Box Box 119)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Q, I", incl. correspondence with Means and Cargill, 1901 Sept. -1906 Dec. (Box Box 119)
  - Hunter Frischkorn - discounts up to 20% on goods, orders, Ingersoll, Sargeant compressors, etc. and miscellaneous correspondence "I", 1902 Jan. -1906 Dec. (Box Box 119)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. correspondence with Means, Carnegie Steel Co., Carey Machinery, Capital City Supplies, Evans Cabell, Cambria Steel Co., correspondence with H. G. Merry, Coke - K. & M. production, Clinton Fire Brick Work - sales, Cincinnati Iron Store, Chicago Pneumatic, sales by sellers promotion etc., 1892 Oct. -1912 March; (5 folders) (Box Box 120)
  - Dalton, Nash, incl. correspondence with Means, Dalton, Nash & Co. - sales, conditions, prices, Invoices for the Federal Insurance Co., Lighterage charges, production quotes, sales by company, prices, shipments, quality control problems, lighter payments, 1901 April -1905 March; (6 folders) (Box Box 121)
  - Dalton, Nash, incl. correspondence with Means, difficulties on quality, shortages - "universal" - on order, more information on A. & L., 1901 March -April (Box Box 122)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. H. G. Merry, Marion Steam Shovel, Manning & Squire - agents of Passaic Zinc Co. - chemist, Mackey Print Paper Co., Thomas A. Mack - sales memo's and correspondence, 1891 Feb. -1895 March; (3 folders) (Box Box 122)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-M", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry, Thomas Mack and H. R. Durkee commission orders, tax tickets sent to Low Moor from Allegheny County for employees, Low Moor to pay out of men's next month wages, other treasurer correspondence, county levies, 1897 April -1902 Dec. (Box Box 123)
  - Hunter Frischkorn, incl. payments and orders, prices on desired goods quoted, explanations of delays, information on when to expect shipment, etc., 1900 Sept. -1902 July; (2 folders) (Box Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "F", incl. Fidelity & Casuality Co. - employer forms - enquiring about employee's finances, work habits; Fenwick Shipping out production one month and supplier correspondence, 1901 Jan. -1902 Sept.; (2 folders) (Box Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P, Q", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry, Public Telephone Co., job solicitations, Iron Suppliers, rubber, 1896 May -1900 July (Box Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P", incl. correspondence with Means and Merry, locomotive and steel suppliers, ads, price quotes, H. K. Porter - contracts Pittsburgh Locomotive & Car Works contract, Pennsylvania Steel Co., steel, rail, and engine suppliers, Robert Parrish - Counsel - alert to possible laws he feels detrimental to Low Moor interest, also claims decisions, electrical goods suppliers, 1896 April -1900 Jan.; (3 folders) (Box Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D-R", incl H. G. Merry correspondence, Hot Water Co., newspapers, iron, wall paper dealers, 1891 May -1899 July (Box Box 125)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry, C. & O. Railway, coal companies, Dukson Mfg. Co. - on new switching locomotives, Dewey Bros. Millers, leather, paint, lubrication suppliers, Davis-Coldy Ore Roaster - interest in sale, Davis, Relly - locomotive, Davis Casting Machine Co., Davis Hartman - parts for machinery, blast furnace, parts suppliers, 1891 Sept. -1899 Nov.; (4 folders) (Box Box 125)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B-L", incl. Merry - general manager, Wickes manager of mines, Earle Bacon - Mining Engineer - Ore Washing Works, Pipe and foundry companies, conveyor belts, 1906 March -1907 Sept. (Box Box 125)
  - Lynchburg Foundry Co., incl. Wickes manager of the mine, and Means president, pipes - ordered, redesigned slow capacities, etc., 1907 June -Nov. (Box Box 125)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "I-S", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry, Norfolk & Western Railway - want Low Moor to exert pressure against Wilson Tariff Bill (1893) - coal, iron, lumber and free lists, E. H. Noyes shipper of provisions, job application references, 1891 March -1899 Sept. (Box Box 126)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "N", incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry, New River Coal & Coke, National Valley Bank of Staunton - Low Moor account deposit receipts, Pneumatic Tools and Raw Material suppliers, information on prices, 1889 Oct. -1900 Jan.; (2 folders) (Box Box 126)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. Sullivan Machinery Co., Machine part suppliers, correspondence with Cargill, B. F. Sturtevant - engineering on pumps Stringfellow & Webster - iron purchasers request information on Low Moor for possible purchases, Stromberg Carlson - telephones, Southern Bell Telephone - quality of service - off and on and rectifications made, Southern Iron & Equipment Co. railroad, cars, parts, other finished goods, Sprague Electric - hoses, Standard Sale & Supply Co. - scale in information, Wickes and E. C. Means, scales suppliers, Standard Scales, Standard American Weighing & Recording Co., 1885 March -1906 Sept.; (5 folders) (Box Box 126)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. correspondence with Means, C. & O. Coal & Coke Co. - shipments ordered, filled, delayed, etc., 1905 Feb. -Aug. (Box Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. correspondence with Merry and Means, pump and engine companies and other raw material suppliers, Baldwin Locomotive Co., Burt Mfg. Co. - machinery designed to save lubrication Cargill correspondence, 1899 Oct. -1907 Sept.; (2 folders) (Box Box 127)
  - Lyman-Wickes correspondence, Potts Creek development, 1905 Nov. -1906 Feb. (Box Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A", incl. Means and Cargill correspondence, Adams Bros.- Payne - building supplies, American Car & Foundry, Allegheny Ore & Iron - problem of turnaround in cars invoices of shipments made, Allis Chalmers - engine installed, Allegheny Iron & Steel - purchases, routing, delays, etc., Ashland Steel, Ashland Fire Brick, suppliers of raw goods, 1902 Feb. -Nov.; (3 folders) (Box Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-L", incl. correspondence with Wickes and Means, A. S. Cameron Steam Pumps specifications, orders, operating problems, performance cost, etc., other pump companies contacted, 1907 June -Aug. (Box Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D", incl. correspondence with Cargill and E. C. Means, E. Dillon & Sons - rock line suppliers, De Camp Bros. of St. Louis - won't sell Low Moor Iron, E. J. Dugcont - powder and dynamite, H. R. Durkee - sales, Joseph Dixon Crucible Co., 1904 Oct. -1906 May; (2 folders) (Box Box 128)
  - Dalton, Nash, incl. correspondence with E. C. Means, invoices, sales reports on competitions, market conditions in the northeast, contracts, prices, orders, shipments, prices, 1905 Sept. -1906 May; (3 folders) (Box Box 128)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. correspondence with E. C. Means and S. G. Cargill, Frank Lyman - treasurer and personal correspondence, deposits of Low Moor bank transfers, Lynchburg Foundry Co. - large purchases, cost sheet, coal dept., operating cost of Low Moor Railroad for the first four months, Dolly Ann Mines at a loss, 1887 April -1904 Dec.; (2 folders) (Box Box 129)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G-L", incl. Means and Cargill, parts list specification - 2 boilers and blast furnace, W. J. Loth Stove Co. - iron purchasers, shipping orders, Joseph Gregg - grain shipper, 1898 July -1904 Aug. (Box Box 129)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G", incl. E. C. Means, S. G. Cargill, H. G. Merry correspondence, John Gordon commission sales, Grant & Williams, George B. Gaines - explosives, Glamorgan Pipe & Foundry, Georgia Lumber Co., 1897 Nov. -1900 Aug.; (2 folders) (Box Box 129)
  - B. F. Goodrich Co., Glamorgan Pipe & Foundry Co., 1898 Oct. -1900 May (Box Box 129)
  - John Gordon - Iron Commission, incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry, orders prices, freight rates, shipping and billing errors, 1898 March -1900 Aug. (Box Box 130)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. correspondence with Means and Cargill, W. J. Loth Stove Co. - major purchases, Lynchburg Foundry Co., Lyman correspondence - payments, transfers, difficulties getting coal cars, 1904 Dec. -1906 Sept.; (3 folders) (Box Box 130)
  - Pumps, incl. correspondence from Wickes, manager of the mines, to pump manufacturers, 1907 May -Sept. (Box Box 131)
  - Pipes, incl. correspondence from Wickes to pipe companies, 1906 Aug. -1907 April (Box Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. correspondence with S. G. Cargill and E. C. Means, Westinghouse - requests for price, bills, etc., Warren Webster & Co. - steam heating, Weir Frog Co. - switch rails, pipe, rail, metal parts suppliers, Merry correspondence, 1896 Jan. -1904 Oct.; (3 folders) (Box Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. E. C. Means correspondence, steam heating, West Virginia Pulp & Paper, 1897 April -1902 May (Box Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W-V", incl. Merry, Means correspondence, Western Pig Iron statistics, Westinghouse; Church, Kerr & Co. - figures, Vacuum Oil Co. - lubrication, 1891 Jan. -1902 March (Box Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "R", incl. Merry correspondence, Rich Patch Iron shipments made; John Roebling and a number of iron purchases, 1890 Oct. -1893 Dec. (Box Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "U-W", incl. Merry and Means correspondence; transportation, raw material suppliers graphite, cement, stone, lumber, Union Rail Line; Union Steam Pump Co., Battle Creek Steam Pump Co., 1898 Aug. -1905 April; (3 folders) (Box Box 132)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. E. C. Means correspondence, Barker-Jennings - locomotives, 1899 July -1900 March (Box Box 132)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-B", incl Baldwin Locomotives - purchase, 1896 Nov. -1900 Feb. (Box Box 132)
  - Stack Mines and Lyman correspondence, incl. Wickes, manager of the mines, Lyman correspondence - Potts Creek wages, foreign labor, etc., Stack Mine Blasts (1922-1925), 1905 March -1907 Sept. (Box Box 132)
  - C. & O. Railroad, incl. E. C. Means - various C. & O. agents on shipments, difficulties, etc., 1906 Jan. -July (Box Box 132)
  - C. & O. Coal & Coke, incl. Cargill correspondence, billing orders, misshipments, account drops, etc., 1906 June -Sept. (Box Box 132)